你一定是我的幸运星You must be my lucky star
因为无论你在哪 都把我照亮'
Cause you shine on me Wherever you are
只要想起你 我就开始发光I just think of
you And I start to glow
我需要你的光芒 宝贝你是知道的And I need your
light And baby you know
- 嗯哼 看镜头 - 星光 闪亮…
- Uh-huh. And look to camera.
- Starlight, starbright...
不错 继续Work it and work it.
幸运小精灵要加入合唱Lucky leprechaun coming in for the chorus.
星光 闪亮 今晚我看见的第一颗星Starlight, starbright
First star I see tonight
左边一下 右边一下 左边再来两下And hup, and
hup, and double to the left.
你跳对了You got it!
我的天啊Oh, my goodness.
停Cut.
山姆格林菲尔德 你的运气可真坏You sure have bad luck,
Sam Greenfield.
谁 我Who, me?
抱歉 山姆Sorry, Sam.
重新开始前 我们得让你有点好运气Before we go again, we
gotta get you some good luck.
跟我来Come on.
夏日乐园 女生之家
也许这里面的某样东西能帮上忙Maybe one of these will help.
你的藏品又增加了I see you've added to your collection.
- 是啊 我的幸运纸鹤… - 不错
- Yep. My lucky crane...
- Nice.
幸运德国猪…lucky German pig.
我的日本招财猫My Japanese waving cat.
- 这个运气超级旺 - 酷
- That one's super lucky.
- Cool.
我的瑞典玩具马 我把我所有的幸运物品都放在一起My doll horse from Sweden.
I put all my good luck charms together
这样我的周末访问就能一切顺利so that my weekend
visit will go just right.
聪明的想法Smart thinking.
- 他们周五会来接你 对吗  - 是的
- They're picking you up on Friday, right?
- Yep.
我看见你已经给幸运硬币留好了位置And I see you've got your
lucky penny spot ready to go.
是的 这是我需要的最后一样东西Yeah!
It's the last one I need.
找到一枚硬币 捡起来…Find a penny, pick it up...
然后一整天你都会有好运气and all day long, you'll have good luck.
我们去把视频录完Let's go finish the video.
- 我们走吧 - 山姆 你在这里
- Let's do it.
- Sam? There you are.
社工正等着你呢The social worker's waiting for you.
山姆 再见 祝你好运Bye, Sam.
Good luck!
她要去哪里Where's she going?
她超龄了She's aging out.
我们都会想念你的Well, we're all gonna miss you around here.
我再多待几天会怎么样What if I just
stayed a couple more days?
- 山姆 我们讨论过了 而且… - 我知道
- Sam, we talked about this, and--
- I know.
我就想看在海瑟的份上I just thought, for Hazel's sake,
也许我能多留在这里几天 在她临走时送她一下maybe I could stick around here a
bit longer, see her off for her visit.
如果我能决定的话当然可以 但你现在18岁了If it were up to
me, yes, but you're 18 now.
- 必须如此 - 就多两天
- This is how it works.
- Just two more days.
我知道你现在很紧张 但是你要搬去属于自己的家了I know you're nervous, but
you're moving into your own place.
会很棒的It is gonna be great.
而且你可以周五探访时间回来And you can come
back Friday for visiting hours,
在海瑟离开前看望她see Hazel before she goes.
是的 好吧Yeah, okay.
我在楼下等你I'll see you downstairs.
我不确定是否准备好了Not sure I'm ready for this.
我最喜欢拥抱了I love hugs.
我知道I know.
别觉着我要离开 就意味着我们不能完成那个视频Don't think my leaving
means we won't finish that video.
与此同时 我还是会继续练习舞蹈动作的In the meantime,
I'll keep practicing those dance moves.
周五你离开前 我会来看你I'll see you Friday before your visit.
如果你找到一枚幸运硬币的话And if you find a lucky penny?
我一定会带上它I'll bring it for sure.
嗨 萨曼莎 今天是个大日子Hi, Samantha. Big day.
这些是你的档案Those are your records.
我的一生都在盒子里了My life in a box.
- 准备好了吗  - 准备好了
- All set?
- All set.
特纳之家 山姆格林菲尔德 档案
山姆的第一次周末访问
科尔曼之家
山姆格林菲尔德 解除看护
儿童安置机构
科尔曼之家 帕克尔之家
我想我们不够幸运 没能为你找到永久家庭I guess we weren't lucky
enough to find you that forever family.
是啊 在这点上确实错失良机了Yeah, sure missed
the boat on that one.
好的一面是 现在我可以 把所有希望都抛在脑后了On the upside, now I
can put all that hoping behind me.
我希望你能喜欢你的新家Well,
I hope you like your new place.
你必须上学或全职工作才能保留公寓You have to be in school
or working full-time to keep the apartment.
我上周就开始上在线课程了I started my online classes last week,
而且明天早上8点我就开始新工作and I start my new
job tomorrow at 8:00 a.m.
太好了Excellent.
我想你需要这些I suppose you'll be needing these.
谢谢你Thank you.
我猜这就是为什么 里维拉女士建议我带个备用的I guess that's why Ms.
Rivera suggested I bring a spare.
这样可能更安全This is probably safer.
那么 你会每周来看我吗 还是…So, will you be
checking in on me weekly, or...
机构的人下个月会给你打电话Someone from the agency
will call you next month,
但除此之外 你就完全靠自己了but otherwise you
are officially on your own.
谢谢Thanks.
祝你好运Good luck.
《基础商务入门》
《商务入门》 二手书
上午8点 鲜花店
"别迟到""Don't be late."
好吧 老天 你觉得自己很强悍吗Okay, universe, think you're pretty tough?
老天爷 看招Take that, universe.
鲜花店
艺术用品 花卉 工艺品 家居装饰
比尔 谢谢 你记得给水仙花浇水了吗Thanks, Bill.
Did you remember to water the daffodils?
还有如果你可以And if you could,
拆开独角兽夜灯的箱子 给生日气球补货unbox the unicorn night-lights
and restock the birthday balloons.
最后 我保证这是最后一件事Lastly,
I promise you this is it.
在开始营业前把卫生间再仔细检查一遍Go to the bathrooms and give
it a once-over before we open.
只要继续让我的商店看起来漂亮就好Just keep making my store look pretty.
早上好 哈蒙德先生…哈蒙Good morning, Mr. Hammond-
- Harmon.
山姆 很准时 我喜欢Sam! Right on time.
I love that.
比尔 我希望你学着点I hope you're taking notes, Bill.
还有 叫我马文就行And, please, just call me Marv.
马文 明白了Marv, got it.
你可能是我做出的最好的决定You may be the
best decision I ever made.
亮片 让你的作品熠熠生辉
嗨 马文Hi, Marv.
嘿 山姆 你从来没有 在你的简历中提到过…Hey,
Sam, you never mentioned that...
你会耍杂技you had circus skills on your résumé.
除非是我读漏了Unless I read past that or something.
抱歉打扰您Sorry to bother you.
这怎么会在你的…How did it get on your--
你知道吗You know something?
别紧张 我为你安排了一份完美的工作Don't sweat it.
I got the perfect task for you.
来吧 山姆 你能在室外做的工作Here we go, Sam.
A job you can do outside.
回收推车Cart patrol.
好耶Yay!
我敢肯定 明天你的运气会好些You'll have better luck tomorrow.
I'm sure of it.
马文 我一直都希望如此I keep hoping, Marv.
夏日乐园 女生之家 姓名 进入时间 出来时间
我很高兴你在这里I'm really glad you're here.
- 出什么事了吗  - 她的周末访问刚被取消了
- Did something happen?
- Her weekend visit just got canceled.
糟糕Oh, no.
是啊 他们打电话来时 她正在门廊上等着Yeah, she was waiting
on the porch when they called.
他们重新安排时间了吗Did they reschedule?
没有 但有一对夫妇 想在周日下午来做第一次访问No, but there's a couple who wants
to come for a first visit on Sunday afternoon.
安置名单 海瑟默菲 凯利家
嗨Hey, you.
他们不来了They're not coming.
我知道 海瑟 我真的很抱歉I know. I'm so sorry, Hazel.
如果我永远找不到永久家庭怎么办What if I never find a forever family?
这次只是小小的坏运气This was just a little bad luck.
你当然能找到Of course you will.
你就没找到You didn't.
对 但你不是我Yeah, but you're not me.
你是幸运小精灵 记得吗You're the lucky leprechaun, remember?
你总是能找到金子 找家庭是一样的You always find the pot of
gold, and this will be no different.
你会找到永久家庭的You'll find your forever family too.
谁知道呢Who knows?
也许是周日来的那对夫妇Maybe the couple coming on Sunday.
也许就是他们家Maybe it'll be them.
是的 也许吧Yeah, maybe.
也许在那之前 你能帮我找到一枚幸运硬币And maybe you'll find
me a lucky penny before then.
两姐妹咖啡馆
滚吧 猫 把你的坏运气带走Beat it, cat.
Take your bad luck with ya.
现在是两个人一起吃了And now it's a table for two.
为什么就不能顺顺利利呢Why couldn't it have just worked out?
抱歉 我没跟你说前面的部分Sorry,
I didn't tell you the first part.
我的朋友海瑟今天本可能 离被收养又近了一步My friend Hazel could have been
one step closer to getting adopted today,
但这并没有发生but it didn't happen.
她的周末访问被取消了Her weekend visit got canceled,
这听起来可能不是什么大事which probably doesn't sound like a big deal,
但相信我 这是大事but believe me, it is.
你找到永久家庭的机会只有那么多You only get so many
chances to find a forever family,
而且年龄越大越难找到and the older you
get, the harder it is.
她星期日要见一对新夫妇She's meeting a new couple on Sunday.
我真希望可以给她一点好运气If I could just give
her a little good luck...
但你不能给别人你从未有过的东西But you can't give
someone something you've never had.
但我真希望可以Still, if I could,
而且如果好运气是 你可以真正握在手里的东西and if good luck was something
you could actually hold in your hand,
我会把它都给海瑟I'd give it all to Hazel.
这样的话或许她能找到永久家庭So that maybe she
could find her forever family
而不是像我一样孤独一人and not end up alone like me,
坐在马路边sitting on a curb,
对着一只猫说话talking to a cat.
不客气You're welcome!
海瑟 真没想到Well, what do you know, Hazel.
找到一枚硬币 把它捡起来 整天都会有好运气Find a penny, pick it up,
and all day long, you'll have good luck.
家庭作业上传成功
幸运硬币是真的Lucky pennies are real.
里维拉女士 我一会儿下班后去看看可以吗Ms. Rivera, hi.
Is it okay if I stop by after work later?
我为海瑟明天的访问准备了特别的礼物I have something special for
Hazel for her visit tomorrow.
太棒了Great.
请不要告诉她 我想给她一个惊喜And please don't tell her.
I want it to be a surprise.
太好了Yes!
大吉大利 今晚吃鸡Winner, winner, chicken dinner.
嗨 马文Hi, Marv.
好吧 有人干得顺手了Well, somebody found their groove.
明天你不用回收推车了No cart patrol for you tomorrow.
我有一托盘的玻璃器皿专门让你负责I got a pallet of
glassware with your name on it.
- 听上去很棒 - 祝你有个愉快的夜晚
- Sounds great.
- Have a nice night.
谢谢 我会的 我要去 给我的朋友海瑟一个惊喜Thanks. I will.
I'm off to surprise my friend Hazel.
自动冲水9000
保证 "每次都能冲水"
我愚蠢的坏运气My stupid bad luck.
你回来了You're back.
记得我告诉过你 我想为我朋友海瑟So, remember I told you I
wanted good luck for my friend Hazel
明天的访问带来好运气for her visit tomorrow?
你猜怎么着Well, guess what?
你走了以后 我找到一些After you left last night,
I found some.
没错 我真的找到了一枚幸运硬币That's right.
I found an actual lucky penny.
结果呢 我把它冲进了马桶And what did I do?
I flushed it down the toilet.
你做了什么You did what?
你把我的硬币冲进了马桶You flushed my penny down the toilet?
你为什么要那么做What did you do that for?
你刚才说话了You just talked.
原来是你It was you.
你给了我那枚幸运硬币You gave me that lucky penny.
拜托 我想再要一枚Please,
I just need one more.
等等Wait!
等等 回来Wait!
Come back!
啊Huh?
我只需要为我的朋友海瑟要一枚硬币I just need a
penny for my friend Hazel.
啊Huh?
我今天过得怎么样  很好 谢谢你 真是太好了How was my day? It was lovely! Thank you.
Just brilliant.
我丢了旅行硬币 还被追着穿过整个城市Lost my travel penny
and was chased across the city
被一个不屈不挠的人类僵尸追by an unrelenting human zombie.
总是用令人厌恶的长密码Always with the obnoxiously long password.
输入正确Got it.
现在 关于那个硬币的问题 鲍勃 你为什么自言自语Now, about that penny problem.
Why you talking to yourself, Bob?
只是在练习 这样我被永远驱逐时 就有一个可以倾诉的人…Just practicing so when I'm banished forever,
I'll have someone to talk to--
不好No.
错误
你到底是什么样的疯狂人类What manner of crazy human are you?
你是什么样的会说话的疯狂猫What kind of a
crazy talking cat are you?
一只幸运的苏格兰猫 显而易见A lucky Scottish one, obviously.
但黑猫代表着不幸But black cats aren't lucky.
在苏格兰黑猫被认为 是超级幸运星 真谢谢你In Scotland, black cats are
considered very lucky, thank you very much.
- 这里是苏格兰吗  - 不是
- Is this Scotland?
- No!
而且人类不能来这里And humans cannot be here.
- "这里" 是哪里  - 你现在就得离开
- Where's "here"?
- You need to leave. Now.
我会离开的 没问题I'll leave, no problem,
只要你再给我一枚幸运硬币as soon as you
give me another lucky penny.
我没给过你硬币I did not give you a penny.
当你用那美味的肉面包引诱我时 它从我的项圈里掉了出来It fell out of my collar when
you lured me over with that tasty meat bread.
那叫帕尼尼It's called a panini.
随便啦 都是为了窃取我旅行硬币的伎俩Whatever.
It was all just a ploy to steal my travel penny.
旅行硬币Travel penny?
我们这些来自幸运之地的生物 在你们的世界里并不幸运We creatures from the Land
of Luck aren't lucky in your world,
为了安全起见 我们会随身带一些硬币so we carry some
with us just to be safe.
你刚是说了 "幸运之地" 吗Did you
just say, "Land of Luck"?
藏起来Hide!
先生们 下午好Good afternoon, gentlemen.
鲍勃 欢迎回来 到达时间18点06分Welcome back, Bob.
Arrived back 18 hundred hours and six minutes.
小精灵Leprechauns?
另一边有什么不寻常的事发生吗Anything unusual happen on the other side?
没有Nope.
鲍勃 部门：A113 硬币已归还
我看见你找到了一条被挡住的运气线I see you located one blocked luck line.
那个施工现场 难怪That construction site.
No wonder.
是的 看起来保利的爆米花摊 逐渐站稳了脚跟Yep, looks like Paulie's
popcorn pop-up is putting down roots.
不是问题 打两个勾 线就绕着走了Not a problem.
Two ticks and around she goes.
我还想说三个就行了I'd wager three might do the trick.
昆恩 你是对的Right you are, Quinn.
运气再次畅通无阻Luck flowing freely once again.
你们看到杰瑞了吗  他通常在这里为我办理登记手续Say, you guys seen Gerry around?
He's usually here to check me in.
他在硬币仓库 他们需要人帮忙He's down at the Penny Depot.
They needed an extra hand.
硬币仓库Penny Depot?
我们就是替他迎接他的划线猫So we're covering his line cat returns.
杰瑞说他总是帮你上交你的旅行硬币And Gerry said he always turns
in your travel penny for ya,
所以现在请交给我们吧so we'll be taking that now.
不好Uh-oh.
这样吧 我今天会自己把它交上去的You know what,
I'll just turn it in myself today.
鲍勃 你要这么说的话 祝你好运吧If you say so, Bob.
Good luck with that.
是的 替我们向船长问好 我们知道她有多爱你Yeah.
Say hi to the Captain for us.
We know how much she loves you.
但是她不爱它But she doesn't love him.
- 我是在说反话 - 你太聪明了
- I was being ironical.
- You're so clever.
我都做了些什么What have I done?
我不应该停下来吃人类的食物I wasn't supposed to
stop and eat human food.
我绝不应该在一个人类面前讲话I definitely wasn't supposed to
talk in front of a human.
而且我肯定不应该 让那个弄丢我旅行硬币的人类And I sure as heck wasn't supposed
to let the human who lost my travel penny
跟随我进入传送门follow me through the portal!
好吧 但那些小精灵刚刚提到硬币仓库Okay, but those leprechauns just
said something about a Penny Depot.
也许我们能在那拿到一枚Maybe we could get one there.
只有小精灵才能进入 你又不是小精灵Only leprechauns are allowed inside,
and you are not a leprechaun!
但也许我可以是But maybe I could be.
什么What?
你以为你能大摇大摆地 走进精灵更衣室吗You think you're just gonna
march down to the leprechaun locker room
而且借到衣服and borrow some clothes?
- 这主意太棒了 我们走 - 不 等一下 停
- Brilliant idea. Let's go.
- No, wait. Stop!
站住Just stop!
嗨 鲍勃 一切都还好吗Hey, Bob.
Everything okay?
是的 就是伸展一下我的腿Aye, just stretching my legs.
好吧Okeydokey.
即使你能伪装成一个大得不像话的精灵Even if you could masquerade
as some freakishly big leprechaun,
不交回硬币我也无法过船长那一关I can't get past the
Captain without turning in a penny.
如果你交回这个会怎么样What if you turned in this?
这是一颗纽扣This is a button.
他们早晚会发现的And at some point, they will discover it,
如果他们发现的时候我手里没有幸运硬币 我就会被放逐and if I don't have a lucky penny in hand when they do,
I'll be banished.
好吧 但也许这颗纽扣 能给我们争取一些时间Okay, but maybe the
button buys us a little time
让我们从硬币仓库拿到一枚幸运硬币until we get a lucky
penny from the Penny Depot.
- 然后我就借来给我的朋… - 给你的朋友海瑟
- Then I'll borrow it for my frie--
- For your friend Hazel.
是的 我明白那个部分了Yes,
I've got that part.
怎么了 你说了100遍了What?
You said it, like, a hundred times.
我们就去硬币仓库拿一枚硬币We'll go to the Penny
Depot to get one penny.
我先用 然后就归你了I use it first,
and then it's all yours.
而且到时我会离开And then I'll leave.
你永远都不会再见到我You'll never see my face again.
太棒了 顺便说一下 我叫山姆Great.
I'm Sam, by the way.
在商言商 名字不重要This is strictly business.
Names are unimportant.
但我已经听见他们叫你鲍勃了But I already heard them call you Bob.
好吧 是的 我叫鲍勃Fine.
Yes, it's Bob.
划线猫们 欢迎回来 现在放下你们的硬币继续往前走Welcome back, line cats.
Now, drop your pennies and move along.
好了 我们走 小猫咪们That's it.
Let's go, kitty cats.
放下你们的旅行硬币Drop your travel pennies.
继续走Keep it moving.
琼妮 今天是64区Sector 64 today, Joanie.
尼日利亚Nigeria.
船长 另外一边见Catch you on the flip side, Cap.
- 那是船长  - 是的 就是她
- That's the Captain?
- Aye, that's her.
她很不喜欢我She really doesn't like me.
也许她不是爱猫之人Maybe she's not a cat person.
其他的猫她都喜欢Well, she likes the other cats just fine.
那么 计划是什么So, what's the plan?
好的 你从那边的那扇门溜出去 我来吸引船长的注意力Right.
You sneak out that door over there.
I'll keep the Captain busy.
你安全了 我就投下硬币和你在那边见面When you're clear,
I'll drop in the button and meet you on the other side.
简单 祝我们两个都好运Simple.
Good luck to us both.
幸运硬币悦耳的叮当声The sweet clankety-clack of lucky pennies.
世界上没有比这更好听的声音了There's no better sound in the world.
鲍勃 你在等什么 投硬币Bob, what are you waiting for?
Drop your penny.
好的 船长 它就在这里Aye,
I got it right here, Cap.
但是首先 您今天过得还好吗But first, how's
your day been so far?
好吧 鲍勃 你有什么企图Okay,
Bob, what are you up to?
一只猫为什么不能 问问它的老板今天过得如何Why can't a cat ask
how his boss's day is going?
鲍勃 因为这很奇怪Because it's weird, Bob.
鲍勃 因为你从来没问过我任何事情Because you never
have asked me anything, Bob.
鲍勃 因为我们甚至都不喜欢彼此Because we don't
even like each other, Bob.
鲍勃 因为你一直让我觉得不舒服Because you give me the
heebie-jeebies, and you always have, Bob.
就是这些吗 那好吧Is that all?
All righty then.
船长 您爱听笑话吗Say,
Captain, do you like jokes?
鲍勃 我只喜欢好笑的Only the funny ones, Bob.
对 那么你会喜欢这个的Right.
Well, then you'll love this one.
1分钱为什么会逮捕5分钱Why did the penny arrest the nickel?
鲍勃 我不知道 为什么I don't know, Bob. Why?
因为它是铜做的Because she was a copper.
不好笑Wasn't funny.
对 这不是我最好的Yeah, not my best.
- 船长 一会见 - 除非我先碰上你 鲍勃
- Catch you later, Cap.
- Not if I catch you first, Bob.
小精灵更衣室 我们来啦Leprechaun locker room, here we come.
雪莉 欢迎回来 继续往前走Welcome back, Shirley.
Keep it moving.
杰瑞
无意打探隐私 但你有手指吗Not to pry,
but do you have fingers?
是拇指 我是多指症患者Thumbs.
I'm polydactyl.
"杰瑞" 是你的朋友 对不对"Gerry." That's your friend, right?
他更像是我的助理He's more like my assistant.
你确定他不会介意吗You sure he won't mind?
杰瑞从来不会介意Gerry never minds.
问题问得够多了And enough with the questions.
在商言商 记得吗 我们不需要了解彼此Strictly business, remember?
We don't need to get to know each other.
是 好的Yeah, okay.
然后他说： "你是河边的舞者吗 "Then he says,
"Are you a River dancer?"
我们忘记检查马桶了We forgot to check the lavvy.
快 在有人看到之前Hurry, before somebody sees.
- 然后他跳起了小吉格舞 - 吉格舞 不可能 你得展示…
- And then he did a little jig.
- A jig? No. You have to show--
女士们 下午好Good afternoon, ladies.
鲍勃 你在这里做什么What are you doing in here, Bob?
对 划线猫有它们自己的更衣室Aye, line cats
have their own locker room.
我只是… 我是…I was just-
- Well, I was--
- 你懂的… - 它在帮我
- You know--
- He was helping me.
它是我运气之地小精灵的定位向导He's my Land of Luck leprechaun orientation guide.
- 我的妈呀 你可真大 - 是的
- Deary me, you're a big lass.
- Aye.
我叫山姆I'm Sam.
你从哪里来Where ya from?
她从… 你懂的…She's from-
- You know--
拉脱维亚 对 她来自拉脱维亚Latvia! That's right.
She's from Latvia.
赛尔莎 克洛达格不是说她在 毛柠檬酒吧遇到一个拉脱维亚人吗Hey,
Saoirse, didn't Clodagh say she met a Latvian guy down at the Hairy Lemon,
并且他也是个大块头and that he was
a real big fella too?
是的 她说过Aye, she did.
好吧 拉脱维亚真厉害 把他们养得这么大Well, cheers to
Latvia for growing 'em big.
我猜不是所有的幸运生物 都像我们这样小 是吧Guess not all lucky
creatures are teeny-toaty like us, eh?
- 很高兴认识你 - 享受接下来的参观吧
- Nice meeting you.
- Enjoy the rest of your tour.
- 要守规矩 - 你太无耻了
- Don't do anything we wouldn't do.
- You're shameless.
她们真小、真可爱They were so sweet and tiny.
而且令人惊讶的是 没平时那么聪明And surprisingly less clever than usual.
她们完全信了They totally bought it.
下一站 幸运硬币Next stop, lucky penny.
- 对 - 并且之后你离开
- Right.
- And then, you leave.
- 对 - 和我一起说
- Right.
- Say it with me.
- 并且之后你离开 - 不 你离开
- And then you leave.
- No, you leave.
是 我知道 开个玩笑Yeah, I know.
It was a joke.
欢迎来到运气之地Welcome to the Land of Luck.
难以置信Incredible.
你好Hey, there.
嗯哼Uh-huh.
早上好Morning.
这边走 我们马上就到硬币仓库This way.
We'll be at the Penny Depot in no time.
- 跟着我站在圆盘上 - 好吧
- Follow me right onto the disc.
- Okay.
出发了Here we go.
只需微笑和招手Just smile and wave.
- 鲍勃 这周一起吃午餐吧  - 好的 一起吃
- Hey, Bob. Lunch this week?
- Aye, let's do it.
好 该换乘了Okay, it's transfer time.
- 鲍勃 早上好 - 嗨 贝蒂
- Morning, Bob.
- Hi, Betty.
山姆 目前来看一切顺利 都没有人注意到你So far, so good, Sam.
No one's even noticed ya.
山姆Sam?
山姆Sam!
你听说乔了吗  他刚加入了运气制造者工会You hear about Joe?
He just joined the luck makers' union.
太棒了 他特别搞笑That's great.
He's hilarious.
你运气到底有多坏Just how unlucky are you?
对 超级无敌坏Yeah, super-duper unlucky.
我真希望你在我们的小交易敲定前 说明了这一点Well,
I wish you would have made that clear before we shook on our little deal.
嗨 各位 你好Hi, guys.
Hi, there.
就是检查一下轨道抓握情况Just checking on the rail grips.
这里没有不幸运There is no unlucky here.
所以如果你想为你的小伙伴 拿到那个幸运硬币 你最好开始混进去So if you want that lucky penny
for your wee friend, you best start blending in.
我一直都努力这么做That's what I was trying to do.
那是你犯的第一个错误Well, that was your first mistake.
幸运生物不用努力Lucky creatures don't try.
他们不必如此They don't have to.
并且停止流汗 他们也不流汗And stop sweating.
They don't do that either.
对 好的Right, okay.
- 我会尽最大努力 - 不对
- I'll try my best.
- Uh-uh.
我是说 我会努力表现得像没在努力一样I mean,
I'll try to act like I'm not trying.
回答得好Good answer.
我们得找到杰瑞We've got to find Gerry.
他知道这些硬币业务都是怎么运作的He'll know how all this penny business works.
他会是那个穿着绿色衣服超级快乐的人He'll be the super cheery one in green.
他们看起来都那样They all look like that.
你好 朋友们 近来可好Slainte, friends.
What is the story?
他在那里There he is.
奥尼尔O'Neill!
奥莱利、奥多诺霍O'Reilly, O'Donoghue.
巴瑞Barry.
克莱瑞斯 我没忘记你And I didn't forget you, Clarisse.
- 你的微萃咖啡就在这里 - 谢谢杰瑞
- I've got your microbrew right here.
- Thanks, Gerry!
- 他考虑得多周到啊 - 杰瑞
- Is he thoughtful or what?
- Gerry!
山姆 这是杰瑞Sam, Gerry.
你好高大You're grand.
那些是我的衣服吗Are those my clothes?
抱歉 鲍勃说你不会介意的Sorry,
Bob said you wouldn't mind.
山姆来自拉脱维亚 到达的时候她的衣服都破了 而且…Sam's visiting from Latvia.
Her clothes got all messed up on arrival and--
所以你住在人类的世界So, you live in the human world?
通常是Usually.
天啊 你有没有吃过烤芝士三文治Oh, man!
Have you ever tried grilled cheese?
我吃过I have.
对 所以 杰瑞 如你所知 猫是不允许进仓库的Right. So,
Ger, as you know, cats aren't allowed inside the Depot,
而且山姆对第一次轮班稍有点紧张and Sam's a wee bit
nervous about her first shift.
所以我在想或许你能护送她进去 教教她So I was thinking maybe you could escort
her in and, you know, show her the ropes.
我真幸运 当然没问题Lucky me.
Of course.
超级简单So, it's super easy.
你坐在椅子上 硬币会自己过来You sit in the
chair, the penny comes to you,
你把它擦干净 然后再送走you polish it up
and send it on its way.
听上去我可以应付Sounds like something I can handle.
你当然可以Of course you can.
幸运小精灵们就是为这种工作而生的Lucky leprechauns were made
for this kind of work.
在叫我们呢That's us.
- 好的 - 去吧 我马上来
- Uh-uh.
- Go ahead. I'll catch up.
好嘞Okeydoke.
我觉得我们应该放弃行动I think we should abort.
什么 为什么What, why?
山姆 你不是幸运小精灵You're not a lucky leprechaun, Sam.
你是一个超级不幸运的人类You're an insanely unlucky human.
- 或许可能你忘记了 - 相信我 我记得
- Or maybe you've forgotten.
- Trust me. I haven't.
你会带来灾难的You'll cause a disaster.
可能不会 杰瑞说我们坐在椅子上 把硬币擦干净Maybe not.
Gerry said we sit in chairs and polish pennies.
我想要把硬币擦干净 你需要拿着硬币And I imagine to polish a
penny, you need to hold a penny.
而且如果我拿着一枚幸运硬币…And if I'm holding a lucky penny--
我明白了 你就会变得幸运I get it.
You'll be lucky.
偷一枚硬币能有多难呢Pocket one penny.
How hard could it be?
山姆 在这里Sam, over here.
- 你坐在我旁边 - 杰瑞 多谢
- You'll sit right next to me.
- Thanks, Gerry.
好的 小精灵们 让我们把这些硬币擦得光亮如新Okay, leprechauns, let's
get these pennies in tip-top shape.
船长就指望我们呢The Captain is depending on us.
现在是擦硬币时间It's penny time!
请记住 很简单 只需要坐在椅子上Remember, there is nothing to it.
Just stay in your chair.
山姆 拿枚硬币Grab a penny, Sam.
前往到达处和离开处
别慌张Don't panic.
你觉得是一个倒霉斑点造成的吗You think it was a
bad luck speck that did it?
更像是一大堆倒霉斑点吧More like a whole boot full.
山姆Sam!
我告诉过你这将是一个灾难I told you this would be a disaster.
我没想到会拿到纽扣 你看见了 对吧Well,
I didn't expect to get the button.
You saw that, right?
是的 我看见了Oh, yes, I saw it.
现在这个纽扣直接回到了到达处和离开处And now that button's headed
straight back to Arrivals and Departures,
船长一定能看见where the Captain will see it for sure.
那么我们要去哪找硬币呢So, where are we
gonna find a penny now?
我们不找了We're not!
都结束了 我们唯一的机会溜走了This was it, our one chance.
而且现在你得离开And now you leave.
不行 我们说好的是 拿到一枚硬币后我才离开No.
The deal was I leave after we get a penny.
交易取消了 没有其他拿硬币的地方了The deal is off.
There's nowhere else to get a penny.
有人需要硬币Someone need a penny?
鲍勃需要Bob does.
它弄丢了硬币 然后我把硬币冲进了马桶He lost his, and then
I flushed it down the toilet--
- 山姆 - 怎么了 他是你的朋友
- Sam!
- What? He's your friend.
- 助理 - 鲍勃 太糟糕了
- Assistant.
- This is terrible, Bob.
你又停下来吃人类的食物了 是不是You stopped to eat
human food again, didn't you?
- 对 我的人类食物 - 山姆
- Yeah. My human food.
- Sam!
你的人类食物 这是什么意思What do you mean, your human food?
杰瑞 我不是拉脱维亚小精灵 我是人类I'm not a Latvian leprechaun, Gerry.
I'm a human.
人类不能来这里Humans cannot be here!
对 鲍勃说过Yeah,
Bob mentioned that.
所以你把你的旅行硬币丢了 还带着一个人类进入了传送门So, you lost your travel penny
and brought a human through the portal.
船长会不高兴的The Captain is not gonna like this.
而且如果她发现了 你会被发配到坏运气之地And if she finds out,
you'll be banished to Bad Luck!
等一下 这里也有坏运气Wait.
There's a Bad Luck here too?
对 不是这里的这里 而是下面的这里Well, not here,
here, but down there, here, yeah.
是我们世界的另外一半It's the other half of our world.
好运气在上面 坏运气在下面Good Luck on top
and Bad Luck on the bottom,
只是他们的那一半不太好only their half isn't so nice.
当然不太好 坏运气能毁掉所触及的一切Of course, it isn't.
Bad luck ruins everything it touches.
鲍勃 为什么你不告诉我 你会被流放到那里Why didn't you tell
me that's where you'll be banished, Bob?
- 你从来没问过 - 因为你说过别再问了
- You never asked.
- Because you said no more questions.
他们叫来了防化小组They called in the hazmats.
是船长 快 躲起来It's the Captain.
Quick, hide.
可能有点难That might be tough.
好的 大家清场All right, everyone, clear out.
疏散这个地区 这样兔子们就可以工作了Evacuate the area so
the rabbits can do their work.
鲍勃 是你吗Bob, is that you?
船长 不是No, Cap.
是我 杰瑞 来自 "到达处和离开处" 记得吗It's me,
Gerry, from Arrivals and Departures, remember?
- 我已经为您工作了100年… - 杰瑞 你什么时候长了尾巴
- I've been working for you for 100 years--
- Gerry. When did you grow a tail?
- 有尾巴吗  - 船长 见到您真高兴
- Is there a tail there?
- Captain, what a delight!
而且这么快就又见面了 我真幸运And so soon. Lucky me.
你在这里干什么What are you doing down here?
就是来看看我的小精灵朋友们Just visiting my leprechaun friends.
鲍勃 你没有朋友You don't have friends, Bob.
船长 它们已经检查了犯罪现场 没有发现坏运气斑点They've scanned the crime scene,
Captain, and found no bad luck specks.
再检查一遍Scan it again.
一个斑点就能让整堆幸运硬币失去运气One speck can de-luckify an
entire pile of lucky pennies.
咱们快离开这Let's get outta here.
所以真的没有 其他能拿到硬币的地方了吗So, there's really no
other place to get a penny?
没有No!
那么鲍勃丢失在人类世界的硬币怎么办What about the ones like Bob's
that go missing in the human world?
如果那些硬币如此珍贵 你们为什么不找回来If they're so valuable,
why don't you go retrieve them?
- 我们会找的 - 我们找
- We do.
- We do?
我们曾经会找Well, we used to.
但自从船长接手安全工作后 还没有丢失过硬币But not one has been
lost since the Captain took over security.
过去 如果一枚硬币丢失在了人类世界The old days, if a travel
penny went missing in the human world,
- 我们会派出兔子无人机 - "兔子无人机"-we'd send
in the bunny drone. -"Bunny drone"?
是的 一种聪明的小机器人 存放在到达处和离开处Yeah.
Clever little robot.
They keep it at Arrivals and Departures.
那么 咱们去拿无人机So, let's go get it.
好的 但是已经十年没用过了Okay!
But it hasn't been used in a decade.
所以首先 我们要拿一块好运水晶启动它So, first, we'll have to grab
a good luck crystal to power it.
- 那么我们从哪拿好运水晶  - 运气地面
- And where do we get one of those?
- The Luck Floor!
等一下Hold up a minute.
我去到达处和离开处启动兔子无人机I'll head to Arrivals and Departures
and fire up the bunny drone
同时你们两个溜进任务控制中心while you two sneak into Mission Control.
等一下 为什么Wait. Why?
那是他们放无人机操控杆的地方That's where they keep the
joystick that controls the drone.
太棒了 但是先拿水晶Great!
But crystal first.
运气地面我们来了So,
Luck Floor, here we come.
但是水晶放在高处 我们需要高个子的人才能拿到But the crystals are up high.
We'll need someone tall to reach it.
- 我很高 - 想都别想
- I'm tall.
- Not a chance.
- 她太不走运了 - 那倒是真的
- She's way too unlucky.
- It's true.
她只需要拿一个 我觉得她能做到She only has to grab one.
I think she can do it.
好吧 我是说 能出什么岔子呢Fine.
I mean, what could go wrong?
老板 精神可嘉That's the spirit, boss.
鲍勃 听上去我们的交易恢复了Sounds like our little
deal is back on, Bob.
- 是的 并且之后你就离开 - 一言为定
- Yes, and then you'll leave.
- True to my word.
那么我们去哪里拿运气水晶So, where do we get the luck crystal?
我们就走到大厅拿一个We'll just walk down
the hall and snag one.
小意思Piece of cake.
他们都盯着山姆 老板 我们怎么办They're all staring right at Sam.
What do we do, boss?
她从拉脱维亚来 世界上最高的小精灵都来自拉脱维亚She's from Latvia.
Tallest leprechauns in the world come from Latvia.
我们是她的运气之地小精灵定位向导And we're her Land
of Luck leprechaun orientation guides.
杰瑞 带路吧Lead on, Gerry.
没错Right!
所以 这是好运气的研发部门 好运气就是在这里创造的So, this is Good Luck
R and D, where good luck is created.
在布朗尼里找到你丢失的婚戒Finding your lost wedding ring in the brownies?
雪莉总能想出最好的主意Shirley always comes up with the best stuff.
等一下 好运气其实是它们想出来的Wait.
They actually think up the good luck?
是的 那两个在快乐的意外部工作Yeah.
Those two work in Happy Accidents,
好运气有很多部门 比如幸运恋爱部one of the many Good
Luck departments like Lucky in Love,
前排停车位部 正确的时间正确的地点部Front Row Parking Spot! Right Place,
Right Time.
你们人类特别喜欢那个You humans love that one.
说到 "人类" 你是指 生活在人类世界的人And by "humans," you mean
the ones who live in the human world,
杰瑞 是不是don't ya, Ger?
完全正确Exactly right.
接下来 幸运的想法被印在想法便签上Next, the lucky ideas
are stamped onto an idea leaf,
然后被送到运气地面and then sent to the Luck Floor.
运气马上就来 五、四、三、二…And luck passing through
in five, four, three, two...
我们接着参观上层怎么样Let's take this tour to
the upper level, shall we?
瓢虫们把便签送到猪头领班那里The ladybugs deliver the
leaves to the Pig Foreman.
然后它制造水晶And he makes the crystals?
不对 是它们制造Nah, they do.
拉脱维亚 她来自拉脱维亚…Latvia.
She's from Latvia. Latvia.
这个放水晶用 珍妮丝说我可以借用它For the crystal.
Janice said I could borrow it.
好的 运气制造者们All right, luck makers!
我们今天的日程安排得很满We've got a full docket today!
早上好 魔力猪Good morning, magical swine!
一条龙A dragon?
对 它是好运之地的首席执政官Yeah, she's the CEO of Good Luck.
而且是唯一能嗅出坏运气斑点的生物And the only creature that
can sniff out bad luck specks.
可能这就是它在这里的原因Probably why she's here.
它肯定已经听说硬币仓库发生的事了She must've heard what
happened at the Penny Depot.
凭你的运气 我不会走太近的With your luck,
I wouldnae get too close.
这里一点坏运气斑点都没有There's not a speck of bad luck here.
这意味着又是时候了Which means it's that time again.
是时候敞开心扉、做只有你们能做的事Time to open your hearts to
do what only you can do.
- 让我听听 - 把希望和喜悦带给世界
- Let me hear it!
- Bring hope and joy to the world!
好运气就是这个作用That's what good luck does.
你们今天创造的运气 可以在明天改变一个人的生活The luck you create
today could change a life tomorrow.
菲尔 祝你今天好运Have a lucky day, Phil.
老板 你也是You too, Boss.
好吧 你们都听到它说的了Okay, you heard her!
让我们制造一些好运气 你们这些创造繁荣的神奇猪们Let's make some good
luck, you prosperity-making wonder pigs!
蹲下Duck down!
它们正在做 它们正在制作水晶They're doing it.
They're making the crystals.
我们只需要一个给兔子无人机用And we just need
one for the bunny drone.
- 好了 山姆 做好准备 - 准备好了
- This is it, Sam. Get ready.
- Ready.
就是现在 山姆 拿一个Now, Sam! Grab one!
我够不着I can't quite reach.
- 跳 - 不行 她运气太糟了
- Jump!
- No, she's too unlucky!
鲍勃 身手不错Nice move, Bob!
好样的 团队Way to go, team!
我去到达处和离开处找无人机I'll go to Arrivals and
Departures and find the drone.
你们两个直接去任务控制中心You guys head straight to Mission Control.
因为你 鲍勃真的有机会了Because of you,
Bob has a real chance.
如果你愿意 可以留着我的外套You can keep
my jacket if you want!
你的朋友真好You have nice friends.
是的 我说过 他只是我的助理Yeah, like I
said, he's just my assistant.
我知道还需要给你拿到一枚幸运硬币I know we'd still need
to get you a lucky penny,
但我为什么不能给海瑟拿块水晶but why couldn't I just
take Hazel one of those?
那样是行不通的It doesn't work that way.
好运气的想法先储存在水晶里 然后被释放出来The good luck idea is
stored inside the crystal until it's released,
并且只有一样东西可以释放它and there's only one
thing that can release it.
- 是什么  - 随机系统
- What's that?
- The Randomizer.
它将水晶粉碎成幸运尘埃It smashes the crystals into lucky dust,
然后通过运气线 将它随机送到你们的世界中then sends it randomly through
the luck lines into your world.
等一下 你是说运气是随机的Wait.
You're saying luck is random?
是的 所以才叫这个名字 随机系统Aye. Hence the name,
Randomizer.
你看 现在就在发生Look, it's happening right now.
- 那些是什么  - 古老的运气石
- What are those?
- The ancient luck stones.
就像电池一样让机器运转Like the batteries that keep the arms spinning.
好运石从上面吸收好运气The good luck stone draws
in the good luck from above,
坏运石从下面吸收坏运气and the bad luck stone draws
in the bad luck from below.
那些一定就是运气线了And those must be the luck lines.
是的 就是它们Aye, that's them.
就像电源线连接着我们彼此的世界Like the power cords connecting our worlds.
那么是谁制造了坏运气So, who makes the bad luck?
主要是树根和小妖精Roots and goblins, mainly.
树根和小妖精Roots and goblins?
我早就应该知道是妖怪们创造的I should have known it would be monsters.
杰瑞 你在吗Gerry, are ya there?
收到 老板 我听得非常清楚10-4.
Reading you loud and clear, boss.
你在哪里Where are you?
正在进入到达处和离开处Entering Arrivals and Departures right now.
好 动作要快Good.
Make it quick.
- 嗨 杰瑞 - 盖尔 昆恩
- Hey, Gerry.
- Gael. Quinn.
任务控制
- 我找到无人机了 - 好 我们在这里
- I found the drone.
- Good. We're here.
- 任务控制 - 太好了
- Mission Control.
- Great.
- 所有兔子的桌上都有一个操控杆 - 完美
- All the bunny desks have a joystick.
- Perfect!
我们用后面那个 这样没人能看到我的屏幕We'll use that back one.
That way no one can see my screen.
但是我们怎么分散兔子的注意力But how are we gonna distract the bunny?
- 也许我可以努力… - 不行
- Maybe I could try--
- Uh-uh!
不能努力 记得吧  我们已经见过你努力会发生什么了No trying, remember?
We've seen what happens when you do.
好吧Okay.
交给我吧 你在这里等着I've got this one covered.
You wait right here.
我是认真的 一动也不许动I mean it.
Don't move a muscle.
它们追踪全世界的运气They're tracking luck all over the world.
这个老奶奶真幸运That's one lucky grandma.
这个看着挺眼熟Now, that looks familiar.
感觉不是随机的 是不是It doesn't feel random, does it?
你今天过得好吗So, how's your day so far?
好Good.
胡萝卜Carrot.
键盘掉了Dropped your keyboard.
看来你得去IT部门拿个新的了Guess you better run off to
IT and grab a new one.
杰瑞 操控杆激活了Joystick activated, Gerry.
我们快要成功了We're nearly there.
我把水晶放进去I'm putting in the crystal.
老板 它准备好起飞了She's ready for takeoff, boss.
太棒了 目标已锁定Brilliant!
The target's been located.
我们让兔子飞起来Let's get that bunny in the air.
"幸运兔子" 行动开始了Operation "lucky penny" is a go!
它归你了She's all yours.
好的Yes!
只要让它进入目标的攻击距离就可以了Just get her within
striking distance of the target.
当足够近时 它能锁定目标When she's close
enough, she'll lock onto it.
我来打开传送门I'll open the portal.
不好 鲍勃 向上看…鲍勃Oh, no! Bob,
look up. Look up. Bob.
噢 你一定是我的幸运星Oh, you must be my lucky star
因为无论你在哪 都把我照亮'
Cause you shine on me Wherever you are
只要想起你 我就开始发光I just think of
you And I start to glow
我需要你的光芒 宝贝你是知道的And I need your
love so baby you know
星光 闪亮 我今晚看见的第一颗星Starlight, starbright
First star I see tonight
星光 闪亮 让一切都变好Starlight, starbright Make everything all right
星光 闪亮 我今晚看见的第一颗星Starlight, starbright
First star I see tonight
星光 闪亮 噢 耶Starlight, starbright Ooh, yeah!
来吧Come on!
一起来Let's go!
耶Yeah!
公共工程部 污水处理厂
噢Ooh!
它在闪 说明它找到硬币的位置了It's flashing!
That means she's located the penny.
我们怎么知道它拿到了How will we know when she's got it?
它会跳一小段舞 兔子最爱跳舞了She'll do a little dance.
Bunnies love to dance.
不用你说You don't say.
今晚照耀着你美丽的身体…Shine your heavenly body tonight...
它在跳舞 它拿到硬币了She's dancing!
She's got the penny!
因为我知道…'
Cause I know...
现在按下 "家" 按钮Now, press the "home" button.
…你将让一切都变好…you're gonna make everything All right
我会等着硬币 你离开那里I'll wait for the penny.
You get out of there.
你可能是我的幸运星You may be my lucky star
宝贝 你对我做了什么 来吧Oh, what you do to me, baby?
Oh, come on
我是最幸运的人I'm the luckiest by far
你怎么没和我说过你会唱歌Why didn't you tell me you could sing?
你从来没问过 不许提问 记得吗You never asked.
No questions, remember?
对 因为我们不需要了解彼此Right, because we don't need
to get to know each other.
所有公民 请注意Attention, all citizens.
投币机里被投了一件非常可疑的物品A very suspicious item was
turned in to the penny drop.
一颗纽扣A button.
一只划线猫用了这颗纽扣 以为它是一枚幸运硬币A line cat used this
button, thinking it was a lucky penny,
结果在人类世界里被一辆三轮车碾过and was run over by
a tricycle in the human world.
别担心Don't worry.
神奇生物超迅速就能康复Magical creatures heal at the speed of light.
看到没See?
上交了这颗纽扣的划线猫 没有上交旅行硬币Whoever turned in this button
did not turn in their travel penny,
也就是说在我们当中有一个硬币小偷which means there is
a penny thief amongst us.
拜托 我没有偷 我只是把它弄丢了Crikey,
I didnae steal it.
I just lost it.
而且罪魁祸首就是这三只猫中的一只And the culprit is
one of these three cats.
通缉 埃尼 埃德纳 鲍勃
糟糕Uh-oh.
大家都知道偷窃好运气的惩罚Everyone knows the punishment for stealing good luck,
就是被流放到坏运之地is banishment to Bad Luck.
所以当心了 硬币小偷So I'm coming for you, penny thief.
鲍勃 如果最后发现是你做的And,
Bob, if it turns out to be you,
我会非常开心的I'm really going to enjoy this.
我们得交回那枚硬币We gotta turn in that penny.
- 无人机回来了 - 它有硬币吗
- The drone's back!
- Does she have the penny?
杰瑞 你看到硬币了吗Do you see the penny, Gerry?
是的 我看见了Yeah, I see it.
杰瑞 拿上它…Grab it, Gerry! Grab it!
我去拿一下手套I just gotta get my gloves.
什么 不行 你在干什么What? No!
What you doin'?
在吸尘器启动前去拿它Get in there and grab
it before the vacuums turn on.
杰瑞 你拿到了吗Did you get it, Gerry?
- 杰瑞 你静音了吗  - 没有
- Are you on mute, Gerry?
- No.
我在这里 但是硬币不见了I'm here but the penny is gone.
- 什么  - 整个无人机都被吸走了
- What?
- The whole drone got sucked right out.
老板 对不起 你是对的 我本应该直接去拿的I'm sorry, boss. You were right.
I should've just grabbed it.
但你在中间地带还能拿到But you could still get
it from the In Between.
- "中间地带"  - 就是人类碎片去的地方-"In Between"?
- Where the human debris goes.
没错 无人机会在六号桶里Exactly!
The drone will be in bin six.
你只是得赶在杰夫之前拿到它You just gotta get
to it before Jeff does.
杰夫是谁Who's Jeff?
希望你不用知道 跟我来Hopefully, you won't have
to find out. Come on.
为什么要叫中间地带So, why do they
call it the In Between?
那是好运之地和坏运之地的中间区域It's the space between the
lands of Good and Bad Luck.
有点像地下室Kinda like a basement.
有进展了Now we're talking.
你按下那个按钮 行吗Hit the button, would ya?
中间地带 坏运之地
你按了哪个键What button did you press?
BL键 地下室层 怎么了BL, basement level. Why?
我说它像个地下室 你应该按中间地带键I said it was like a basement.
You're supposed to push IB,
In Between.
那么 BL代表什么So then, what's BL stand for?
坏运之地 因为你 我们现在要去那里了Bad Luck!
And thanks to you, we're headed there right now.
发生什么了What's happening?
重力转换 坏运之地的重力 和我们是相反的 爬上墙Gravity shift.
Bad Luck's gravity works the opposite way of ours.
Climb the wall!
- 什么  - 马上
- What?
- Now!
山姆 快点 回到电梯里Sam, hurry.
Get back in the lift.
好的 来了Yes, please.
不要No!
如果电梯启动了 就在中间地带和我碰面If the lift takes off,
just meet me in the In Between.
什么 不行 你不能把我留在这下面What?
Oh, no you don't.
You are not leaving me down here.
有一扇小门 你得找到它There's a tiny door.
You just have to find it.
去13号运气塔 过了丢失的袜子药房就是Go to Luck Tower 13,
right past the Lost Sock Dispensary.
- 你到底在说什么  - 听我说
- What are you talking about?
- Listen to me.
13号塔到狗屎研究中心 然后找到紫色的灯光Tower 13 to the Dog Poop
Research Center, then find the purple light.
小门就在那里Tiny door will be there,
介于 "踩上它" 和 "带回家了" 之间somewhere between "Stepped
in It" and "Tracked It in the House."
很容易Piece of cake.
但我不是这里的人But I'm not from here.
对 好吧 这个真的会有帮助 坏运气世界是一面镜子…Right.
Okay, this will really help.
The Bad Luck world is a mirror--
真好 好吧 13号塔 狗屎研究中心 紫色灯光 小门Great. Okay, Tower 13,
Dog Poop Research Center, purple light, tiny door.
小精灵 你在这里做什么Hey! Leprechaun.
What are you doing here?
13号塔Tower 13.
好的 它说是在Okay, he said it was somewhere between
"踩上它" 和 "带回家了" 之间"Stepped in It"
and "Tracked It in the House."
三层Three stories?
这么多的狗屎研究That's a lot of dog poop research.
"在上面打滑 闻得到却找不到""Slipped on it.
Smell it but can't find it."
"没带狗屎袋就出门 撕坏了的狗屎袋""Left the house without a poop bag.
Torn poop bag."
"拉稀了" 恶心"It's a wet one." Gross.
"踩上它""Stepped in It."
还有 "带回家了" 紫色灯光And "Tracked It
in the House." Purple light!
鲍勃Bob?
我能做到 马上就到了I can do this.
I'm almost there!
不好Oh, no.
啊Huh?
鲍勃 是你吗Bob?
Is that you?
真是你It is you.
鲍勃 是我啊 是山姆 往下看Bob! Hey, it's me. It's Sam.
Look down here.
山姆 你做到了Sam, you made it!
- 是啊 - 小心
- Yeah.
- Watch out.
好的 现在就跳Okay, so now jump.
什么What?
坏运气的重力和我们是相反的 记得吗Bad Luck gravity works
the opposite of ours, remember?
对了Right.
下是向上 真是太奇怪了Down to go up, that's just weird.
- 你是怎么知道的  - 知道什么
- So, how did you know?
- Know what?
怎么从坏运气之地来到这里How to get here through Bad Luck?
很简单 坏运气是好运气的镜像Well, simple.
Bad Luck is a mirror image of Good Luck.
- 这里是中间地带  - 不完全是
- And this is the In Between?
- Not quite.
来 帮我一下Come on, give me a hand.
这是中间地带This is the In Between.
杰瑞说无人机在六号桶里Gerry said the drone
would be in bin six.
坏运气尘埃Bad Luck dust!
快抖掉Shake it off.
是杰夫It's Jeff.
别管那个了 藏起来Forget that! Hide!
它是个大嘴巴He is a total blabbermouth.
如果让它看见 我们就永远没机会找到硬币了If he sees us, we'll never
have a chance to find the penny.
杰夫是只独角兽Jeff's a unicorn?
热一下身Warming up the muscles.
我的天啊Heiliger Strohsack.
就像坏运一条街It's like a strasse of bad luck.
各位 怎么回事啊What's happening, guys?
你好Hello.
你差点把我吓死You surprise my heart to stop.
强大的小精灵女士 你还挺高的Mighty leprechaun Fr?ulein! Okay.
Well done, nature.
是啊Yep.
罗伯特 是你吗Robert, is that you?
嗨 杰夫Hi, Jeff.
你好啊Guten Tag.
所以你们俩是朋友So you two are friends?
罗伯特不想要朋友Robert doesn't want friends,
但它很幸运 我不会把 "不" 当作答案but lucky for him,
I wouldn't take nein for an answer.
扫…刷… 它们沾到你鞋上了Zip, zip, zip and whisk, whisk, whisk.
They are stuck to your shoesy.
有的时候会喷出来一点 是吧  来自我那个自制的坏运气仪器Sometimes a little goes... ja?
From my homemade bad luck apparat.
这是我独一无二的混合机器It's my one-of-a-kind mixer machine
那个把坏运气直接送进随机系统that feeds the bad
luck straight into das Randomizer.
- 你能给我展示一下这是怎么运作的吗  - 是的 跟我来
- Will you show me how it works?
- Ja, komm.
有访客实在太让人兴奋了 我很激动 难以掩饰Es ist sehr exciting to have visitors. I'm excited.
I can't hide it.
我马上来 我需要找一片猫砂I'll catch up.
I need to find some kitty litter.
真恶心 罗伯特 再见Sounds gross, Robert. Bye.
事情是这样的 坏运气黏在一起So the thing is,
the bad luck sticks to itself
就像花生酱粘在上牙床一样like the butter of nuts
to the roof of your mouth.
所以你是说坏运气会招致更多坏运气So, you're saying bad
luck attracts more bad luck?
- 因为很多事情一下就说通了 - 是的-'
Cause that would explain a lot.
- Ja.
就像胶水 看到没 那是过去的情况Like glue. See?
That's what used to happen.
所以我制作了一个混合机器 请看 从此没有结块了So I made eine mixing machine, and voilà!
No more clogs.
坏运气直接流向随机系统The bad luck flows right to das Randomizer.
- 杰夫 这真是一流的工程技术 - 多谢
- That's some top-notch engineering, Jeff.
- Danke sch?n.
我现在不叫杰夫了And I no longer go by Jeff.
对 最近我换成了 出生时的名字 海姆达尔Ja, recently I
have reverted to my birth name, Heimdall!
海姆达尔 就像娃娃但是前面加上 "海姆"Heim-dall.
Like, you know, the little doll but first with a "Heim" in front.
好吧 对 当然了 我的名字在我小时候更贴切Okay, ja, sure, the
name fit better when I was younger.
我明白 你不需要说出来I get it.
You don't have to say it.
这是那条龙吗Is that the Dragon?
对 是它 我唯一的真爱Ja, that's her.
Meine one true love.
它给我冶炼了这个吊坠 救了我的命She smelted me this
locket, and she saved my life.
发生什么了What happened?
在我有混合机器之前 我得手动清理坏运气结块Before my mixing machine,
I had to clean out the bad luck clogs by hand.
有一天管道裂了 然后把坏运粉尘喷得我全身都是And one day the pipe, it pl?tzen!
And gesprüht bad luck dust all over me.
那条龙听说后马上召见了我 那是一见钟情The Dragon heard and sent for me sofort.
It was love at first look.
它借给我一枚幸运硬币来对抗坏运气She borrowed me a lucky
penny to counteract the bad luck.
但是坏运气可能久久不散But bad luck can really linger.
我用了四个月才恢复 但那是我一生中最美好的四个月It took four months to recover, but
they were the beste four months of my life.
然后它伤透了我的心And then she broke my heart.
为什么Why?
有时候一些坏运气会通过我的鞋Well, sometimes I would track a
little bad luck into Good Luck
掺进好运气中on my shoesies.
它非常害怕坏运气会对它的生物 和它的世界造成什么影响She was so terrified of what bad
luck might do to her creatures and her world,
所以它跟我分手了so she broke it off.
现在我们都孤身一人And now we're both alone.
真悲伤How sad.
如果能离开这份工作 我会的If I could
leave meine work, I would.
但是我们独角兽从最初就守护随机系统But we einhorn have cared for
the Randomizer since the buttocks of dawn.
太好啦 来货了Goody!
A delivery!
罗伯特 你在这Da bist du, Robert!
你猜怎么着 刚才我在废墟中 找到了一只兔子无人机Guess what? Earlier,
I found a bunny drone in the pile.
对 就一个 对 我想要一套六个Ja, just one. Ja,
I wanted a set of six.
它还在你那儿吗Do you still have it?
在这里Und here she is.
- 里面有枚硬币吗  - 有啊 罗伯特
- Was there a penny?
- Ja, Robert.
但它臭气熏天 所以我把它送回硬币仓库But it was so stinky, so
I sent it up to the Penny Depot
消毒 然后重新投放到流通中to be disinfected
and put back into circulation.
我听说船长因为那枚硬币 把可怜的埃德纳审问了好几个小时I heard the Captain interrogated
poor Edna for hours about that penny.
它很清白 当然She was clean
as a whistle, of course.
所以现在就剩下埃尼和鲍勃两只猫了So now it's down to just two cats,
Ernie and Bob.
我死定了I'm doomed.
不一定 你先藏起来 我要去见那条龙Maybe not. You lay low.
I'm going to see the Dragon.
山姆 你不能去 它会嗅出你的坏运气You can't, Sam.
She'll sniff out your bad luck.
我就想让它嗅出来 而且我不是碰运气That's exactly what I want her to do.
And I'm not taking any chances.
如果那条龙帮了一只工程师独角兽If the Dragon helped an engineer unicorn,
也许它也会帮一只倒霉的小精灵maybe she'll help an unlucky leprechaun too.
如果它发现你是人类 它永远都不会让你回家的If she discovers you're a
human, she'll never let you go home.
我得冒一下险I have to risk it.
我不能放弃海瑟 还有你 鲍勃I can't give
up on Hazel. Or you, Bob.
别走远Don't go far.
如果我拿到了硬币 我们的计划就能继续If I get a
penny, we're back in business.
下午好 我来这里见那条龙Good afternoon,
I'm here to see the Dragon.
我的老天 这只小精灵真高啊Leapin' rabbits!
It's the tall leprechaun.
霍斯伯格 让她进来吧Send her in, Hopsberg.
还有备忘录And the memos too.
一天两次Twice in one day.
今天早上你在运气地面 对吧You were on the
Luck Floor this morning, right?
对 是我Yes, that was me.
我就说嘛I thought so.
运气水平看着和平时一样优秀Luck levels looking excellent as usual.
下周见See you next week.
我非常高兴I'm so happy.
这里很少有能与我对视的生物There are so few creatures here
I can actually look in the eye.
我们这些有地位的幸运女士 应该团结起来 你觉得呢We lucky ladies of
stature oughta stick together, don't you think?
是啊Yeah.
什么味What's this?
兔子们Rabbits!
在鞋下面Under the shoe.
快Hurry!
好多了Much better.
你看 最微小的坏运气 都能关停我们整个运营You see, the tiniest amount of
bad luck can shut down our entire operation.
我们非常努力不让它们进来 但是We work so hard to
keep it out, but, you know,
坏运气时不时就能混进来every so often, bad luck
manages to find its way in.
我很抱歉 我不是故意惹你心烦 我只是…I'm really sorry.
I didn't mean to upset you. I just--
亲爱的 不是你 不是…是坏运气It's not you, dear. Oh, no.
It's bad luck.
这是一种残酷、具有腐蚀性的悲伤和破坏It's a cruel, corrosive agent
of sadness and destruction that--
我同意 很多事情都说得通了I agree.
And it explains a lot.
比如 为什么在硬币仓库一切都乱了套Why it all went haywire
at the Penny Depot for one.
所以那是因为你So that was you.
是的 今天的确漫长难熬Yeah.
It's been a bit of a day.
可怜的无辜小精灵Poor, innocent leprechaun.
我很抱歉你经历了这些 你只是经历了一个坏运气斑点I'm so sorry you had to go through that.
And you only experienced one speck.
想想那些在不幸之地 负责制造这些东西的可怜人吧Think of the poor souls in the
Land of the Unlucky tasked with making the stuff.
你能想象在一生中 每天都和坏运气打交道吗Can you imagine dealing with bad
luck every single day of your life?
- 一个真正悲惨的存在 - 是的
- A truly miserable existence.
- Yeah.
我想对于接受它的人类来说 也没有什么乐趣And I don't suppose it's much
fun for the humans who receive it either.
没有乐趣It isn't.
我在外面做精灵时见过他们I've seen them when I'm out leprechauning.
这些不幸的人类 无论他们怎么努力These unlucky humans, who,
no matter how hard they try,
坏运气总是会出现 将他们击倒 让他们觉得如此…bad luck always shows up just
to beat them down and make them feel so...
孤独Alone.
没错Exactly.
这就是为什么我们要制造好运气Which is why we make
the good kind of luck,
并且尽我们所能多制造一些and as much as we possibly can.
是的Yeah.
因为当你有好运气时 会感觉一切都有可能'
Cause when you have good luck, it feels like anything is possible.
- 我觉得那是因为… - 好运气是喜悦
- I guess it's because--
- Good luck is joy.
对Yes.
以及希望 就像您说的 这是好的那种运气And hope.
It's like you said, it's the good kind of luck.
如果我是宇宙女王 我猜这是我最擅长的一项工作And were I the queen of the universe,
and I suspect it's a job I would excel at,
我想让这个世界完全摆脱厄运I'd rid the world of bad luck altogether!
完全根除它Eradicate it completely.
永远都是好运 没有比这更好的吧Good luck all the
time, what could be better?
没有了Not a single thing.
而且可以肯定 那些人类也会喜欢的And you can bet
those humans would like it too.
是的 他们的世界可能看上去和这个一样Yeah.
Then their world could look like this.
他们应该如此幸运They should be so lucky.
你来这里见我是对的 你…叫什么名字You did the right thing coming to see me. You-
- What was your name?
山姆 我的名字叫山姆Sam.
My name is Sam.
山姆 叫我贝贝Sam.
Call me Babe.
山姆 你知道很多生物都害怕高大的女性You know a lot of
creatures are intimidated by tall women, Sam.
把这个随身携带几天 你很快就会变回幸运的自己Carry it for a few days.
You'll be back to your lucky self in no time.
上一个我帮助过的生物 硬币用了四个月的时间The last creature I helped
needed four months with a penny
才把它的坏运气全驱散until his bad luck was gone.
我听说坏运气很难驱散I've heard it can really linger.
那是我人生中最美好的四个月They were the best
four months of my life.
贝贝 谢谢您Thank you, Babe.
你用完了交回仓库就行Just return it to
the Depot when you're done.
我会的I will.
你会让一个小女孩 和一只幸运的猫高兴坏的You're about to make a little
girl and a lucky cat so happy.
镇定Take it easy!
放下我 我不要被这样粗暴地对待Get off me.
I won't be cat-handled like this.
鲍勃 我们推定是你弄丢了硬币We traced the missing
penny back to you, Bob.
你没有证据You have no proof.
这个纽扣是我们需要的全部证据This button is all the proof we need.
上面都是你多指症的爪印It's got your polydactyl
paw prints all over it.
- 我可以解释 - 太晚了
- I can explain.
- It's too late.
你将被流放到属于你的坏运之地You'll be banished to
Bad Luck where you belong.
妨碍司法 我也应该逮捕你Obstructing justice?
I oughta arrest you too.
我就是想追上鲍勃把这个给它I was just catching up
to Bob to give him this.
你拿到了You got it.
是的 鲍勃 我拿到了Yes, Bob. I did.
一定是从它的项圈里掉出来了Must've fallen right out of his collar.
可能是在你停下来尝那个美味的肉面包时Maybe when you stopped to
try that tasty meat bread.
你真的确定这枚硬币是我的吗And you're absolutely sure this one is mine?
我确定I'm sure.
她真是个救命恩人She's a real lifesaver, this one.
鲍勃 如果你有旅行硬币 为什么要上交纽扣If you had your travel penny,
why did you turn in the button, Bob?
一时糊涂 在投币机里放错了Silly mistake.
I just threw the wrong one into the drop.
当我发现弄错时When I discovered the mix-up,
我直接去了消除污染部去上交I was heading straight back
to Decon to turn it in,
然后我猜就在那时 这个小东西掉了出来and then I guess that's
when the little bugger just slipped out.
就是这样 没有旅行硬币了Just like that, no travel penny.
你懂的You know,
我开始觉得也许是管设备的兔子 给我发了一个有故障的项圈I'm starting to think that maybe
the equipment rabbits issued me a bum collar.
它掉出来不止一次了This isn't the first time
it's got loose, you know.
我明白了I see.
有问题的设备不能接受 鲍勃你是对的Well, faulty equipment is unacceptable, Bob.
You're right.
是的 绝对如此Aye, it most certainly is.
船长 拿去吧Here you go, Captain.
我不敢相信你会那样做 我是说 谢谢你 非常感谢I can't believe you just did that.
I mean, thank you, like, a lot,
但你本可以直接把硬币给你的朋友海瑟but you could've taken that
penny straight to your friend Hazel.
她先用 然后给我 之前说好的Her first, then
me, that was the deal.
我绝不会为了海瑟能有好运气 让你被送到坏运之地I could never let you be sent to
Bad Luck so that Hazel could have good luck.
- 不该这样 - 那该怎样
- It doesn't work like that.
- Well, how does it work?
因为我不想你回家后 我还留在这里愧疚Because I don't want you to
go home and leave me here feeling guilty
因为她现在不能用幸运硬币了that she doesn't get to
use a lucky penny now.
你以为我要回家了You think I'm going home?
等一下 你不走Wait.
You're not?
我来这里是要帮海瑟的I came here to help Hazel,
而且还有一小时她的访问就开始了and I only have one hour
left to do it before her visit.
如果你真觉得愧疚 那么你可以帮我If you're actually feeling
guilty, then you can help me.
但不可能再拿到另一个硬币了But there's no way to get another penny.
我们要做的事情不需要硬币For what we're doing,
we won't need a penny.
我们要做什么What are we gonna do?
我们要去关闭坏运之地We're gonna turn off bad luck.
如果我们关停杰夫的混合机器If we shut down Jeff's mixer machine,
坏运气应该会粘在一起并堵住管道the bad luck should stick to
itself and clog up the pipe
这样它们就无法流入随机系统so it can't travel to the Randomizer.
并且如果没有坏运气进入随机系统And if no bad
luck gets to the Randomizer...
就没有坏运气进入人类世界了No bad luck gets to the human world.
等等 杰夫怎么办Wait.
What about Jeff?
快点…陡坡 是的 陡坡Und schneller. Und schneller. Und steil.
Ja, steil.
沿着山路往下走Go down that berg.
我无话可说I have no words.
是啊 我觉得我们暂时没事Yeah,
I think we're good for a bit.
你知道无法永久关闭这个 对吧You know we
can't do this permanently, right?
当然知道 这时就轮到你出场了Of course not.
That's where you come in.
我会把它再打开I'm gonna turn it back on.
海瑟最多需要两个小时All Hazel needs is two hours tops.
然后我拨动开关就行了And then I flip the switch.
And that's it.
我们扯平了 完事 齐活儿 问题解决 交易完成We're even. Fini, complet. Case closed.
Deal done.
你将永远不会再见到我You'll never see my face again.
太棒了 开始吧Great.
Here goes.
快看啊Look at that.
它开始粘连了It's starting to stick.
起作用了It's working.
我真希望能见到海瑟I wish I could see Hazel.
我想这个我能解决I think I can handle that.
真的吗 她住在咖啡店以东3.2公里处Really?
She lives two miles east of the café.
再和我说一次她为什么这么需要好运气Tell me again why she
needs good luck so badly.
如果她的访问一切顺利 她就能找到一个永久的家If her visit goes well,
she could find her forever family.
那到底是什么Which is what exactly?
是无论发生什么 永远都有人支持你It's the people who are always
there for you, no matter what happens.
这些人不会离开 他们永远都在The ones who don't leave, they stick.
那里There.
- 那是她吗  - 是的
- Is that her?
- Yeah.
看上去那对夫妇随时会到 我就期盼这样It looks like the couple will be there any minute.
It's all I hoped for,
鲍勃 给海瑟一点好运气 我们做到了a little good luck
for Hazel, and we did it, Bob.
我现在好想拥抱你I swear I could hug you right now.
猫类不喜欢拥抱Cats aren't really huggers.
好吧 我最喜欢拥抱了Well,
I love hugs.
所以 好了 交易总算完成了So, that's it then.
Deal finally done.
请替我谢谢杰瑞Please thank Gerry for me.
而且很抱歉 我把他的衣服撑大了And I'm sorry
I stretched out his clothes.
山姆 我很好奇 你现在有什么希望Hey, Sam. I'm curious.
What do you hope for now?
鲍勃 你在问我问题吗Are you asking me questions, Bob?
现在你终于要离开了Now that you're finally leaving,
好像是时候更好地了解你一下了it seemed like a good time
to get to know you better.
既然这样的话In that case,
我想我只是希望可以一生中做些好事I guess I just hope I
can do something good with my life.
并且我的坏运气不会成为障碍 你懂吗That my bad luck won't
get in the way, you know?
是的 我想我明白Aye.
I think I do.
好的 那么就这样了Right.
Well, that's us.
啊Huh?
它来自中间地带 一定出了什么问题It's coming from the In Between.
There must be something wrong.
我以为这是不可能的I didn't think that was possible.
不 海瑟Oh, no. Hazel!
海瑟 不Hazel. No.
不No.
好运石The good luck stone!
这可不行 我需要好运气来锻造一个新的This can't be happening.
I need good luck to forge a new one.
三叶草已经枯萎了 猪不能创造好运气了The clovers are shriveled.
The pigs cannot create good luck.
硬币怎么样了What about the pennies?
只要一枚幸运硬币就够了Just one lucky penny would be enough.
它们都被污染了They're all contaminated!
试试这个Try this one.
它幸运还是不幸Is it lucky or not?
不幸Not.
等一下 老板 你怎么会有那个Wait.
Why do you have that, boss?
这是否意味着你的运气不好呢Does this mean you're not lucky?
我一直都是对的I was right all along.
你是个骗子和小偷 我打赌甚至都不是苏格兰猫You're a liar and a thief.
I bet you're not even Scottish.
我不是I'm not.
实际上 我是英格兰猫I'm English, actually.
在找到那枚硬币前 我在坏运之地生活了八世And I lived eight lives in
bad luck before I found that penny.
是那个硬币让你变得幸运It was the penny that made you lucky.
是的Yes.
我是一只坏运气的黑猫I'm a bad luck black cat.
而且我永远都会是And I always will be.
那是什么意思What does that mean?
人类世界和运气世界的连接The connection between the human
world and the luck world
已经被永远切断了has been severed for good.
但一定有办法解决这个问题 重新连接起来But there must be a way to fix it!
To reconnect.
没有好运气就没有办法Without good luck, there is no way.
但我得去找海瑟 我得回家But I have to get to Hazel!
I have to go home.
你是个人类You're a human?
是的 而且我得回家Yes.
And I have to go home.
山姆 那我们的家怎么办And what about our home, Sam?
我们的存在是为了给你们的世界带来好运 我们现在会怎么样We exist to make luck for your world.
What will happen to us now?
你从不应该来这里You should never have come here.
她只是跟着我She was only following me.
真的很抱歉 我从没想过会发生这些事I'm so sorry.
I never meant for any of this.
我只是想帮朋友I was just trying to help my friend.
相反 你确保了她And instead, you've made sure that she
和所有其他人类都不会再有好运气and no other humans
will ever experience luck again.
我们应该把他们两个放逐到坏运之地We should just banish both
of them to Bad Luck.
那有什么用呢 现在哪里都是坏运气了What does it matter?
It's all bad luck now.
鲍勃 看吧 我就知道你有点不对劲See,
I knew there was something off about you, Bob.
我打心底里就知道I knew it deep in my soul.
只是我没能及时阻止你Only,
I didn't stop you in time.
而且我必须在余生中承受这一切And I have to live with
that for the rest of my life.
山姆 我应该做得更好的I should've been better, Sam.
我本应该把那枚硬币给你的朋友I should've given you
the penny for your friend.
如果我给了 这一切都不会发生了If I had,
none of this would've happened.
但是你担心我会把它弄丢或者再冲进马桶But you were afraid I'd lose
it or flush it down another toilet.
我害怕失去我幸运的生活I was afraid to lose my lucky life.
而且自私到不想去冒险And too selfish to risk it.
你做了正确的选择Well, you made the right choice.
- 我把事情弄得更糟 我总是这样 - 山姆…
- I make things worse.
It's what I do.
- Sam--
你会认为我现在已经吸取了教训You'd think I would have
learned my lesson by now.
哪怕就放弃一次To just lay down for once,
停止这么努力 停止流汗 就像你说的stop trying so
hard, stop sweating, like you said.
我不应该那么说I should never have said that.
是真的It's true.
即使在这里 这个宇宙中最幸运的地方Even here, in the
luckiest place in the universe,
我还能有办法把事情搞砸I still found a way
to screw it all up.
我就是这么知道的And that's how I know.
知道什么Know what?
我的坏运气不是问题 我才是问题That it's not my bad luck that's the problem.
It's just me.
再多的好运气都没办法改变And there's no amount of good
luck that can ever fix it.
我不相信I don't believe that.
你应该信Well you should.
我不仅害了海瑟 还有你 还有…Not only did
I doom Hazel, and you, and--
其他所有人都要过倒霉的一生 而且现在我没办法回去找她and everyone else to a life of bad
luck, but now I can't get back to her.
我只是许多不守承诺的大人中的一个I'm just another adult who broke another promise.
离开就不会回来的那种The kind that leaves and doesn't stick.
我发誓 如果从未遇见我 她会更好的I swear, she'd be
better off if she never met me.
可我不会更好Well,
I wouldn't be better off.
山姆 你不坏You're not bad, Sam.
你是坏的反面You're the opposite of bad,
是某种纯粹的善良 我曾以为人类不可能有like some kind of pure goodness
I didn't think was possible for a human.
你的直觉是分享 比如那块美味的肉面包Your first instinct is to
share, like the tasty meat bread.
或者帮忙 即便帮忙可能让你 无法得到你最想要的Or to help, even if helping might
stop you from getting what you want the most.
并且更疯狂的是 你最想要的 甚至都不是为了自己And what's crazier is what
you want the most isn't even for you.
你以一种我无法理解的方式 为他人谋求好处You want good things for others
in a way that I can't comprehend,
而且为了能做到 你承受了最糟糕的坏运气and you'll endure the worst
bad luck ever to make it happen.
告诉你不要努力是我错了 因为每次你努力时I was wrong to ever tell you
not to try because every time you do,
你都让事情变得更好 我是这么知道的you make things better.
And that's how I know.
知道什么Know what?
你的好朋友海瑟不需要好运气That your friend Hazel doesn't need good luck.
她已经是世界上最幸运的女孩了 因为她有你She's already the luckiest girl
in the world 'cause she has you.
你说你想要一生中做一些好事You said you wanted to
do something good with your life.
你已经做过了You already have.
我没想让你哭I didn't mean to make you cry.
鲍勃 别担心 这是开心的哭Don't worry, Bob.
It's a happy cry.
人类真是太奇怪了Humans are so weird.
一定有办法解决这个问题There's gotta be a way to fix this!
对 并且让你回到海瑟身边Yes, and get you back to Hazel.
但是可能性渺茫But fat chance of that happening.
除非你在那里隐藏了一些好运气 这个…Unless you have some
good luck hidden in there, which--
等一下 你刚才说什么Wait.
What did you say?
"除非你在那里隐藏了一些好运气""Unless you have some
good luck hidden in there"?
- 就是这句 - 是什么
- That's it.
- What is?
在坏运之地有好运气There's good luck down in Bad Luck.
你怎么知道How do you know that?
因为我见过Because I've seen it!
并且你打算马上回到坏运之地去拿And you're planning to go right back
down to Bad Luck and fetch it?
- 那是你的计划  - 对了
- That's your plan?
- Bingo.
欢迎回到坏运之地Welcome back to the Land of Bad Luck.
就像我从未离开过It's like I never left.
好运气就在电梯和狗屎研究中心之间The good luck is somewhere between
here in Dog Poop and the elevator.
好吧 具体描述一下你看到的Okay, describe what you saw exactly.
怪物们聚集在一道绿光周围 这一定是好运Monsters were gathered around this green
light that had to be good luck.
然后铃声会响起And then a bell would ding,
它们开始喊叫 还有火和…and they'd start shouting,
and there was fire and--
- 火  - 对
- Fire?
- Yeah.
只可能是一个地方It could only be one place.
上次我一定是从后门进来的I must have come in
the back door last time.
等一下 先别进去Wait!
Don't go in yet!
鲍勃Bob.
嗨Hi.
完蛋了This is it.
鲍勃 是你吗Bob?
Is that you?
老兄 你到底去哪了Where the heck you been, brother?
萝蒂 你还好吗Hey,
Rootie, how's it going?
- 是鲍勃 - 好久不见
- It's Bob.
- Long time, no see.
- 怪物 嗯  - 你说的怪物
- Monsters, huh?
- You said monsters.
我说的是树根和妖精 它们就是啊I said roots
and goblins, which they are.
嗨 鲍勃Hey, Bob.
- 还有山羊 - 它们怎么认识你
- And goats.
- How do they know you?
我曾在这里度过了几个小时I spent a couple of hours here.
对啊 确切说是八辈子Yeah, try eight lifetimes.
就坐在这里喝着我著名的橘子龙卷风Just sitting here sipping my famous tangerine tornado
谈着如果它能找到一点好运气的话and talking about how if he
could just find a little good luck,
它最终会幸福he could finally be happy.
鲍勃 我们以为你死了We thought you were dead, Bob.
是啊 萝蒂甚至把你的酒吧凳收了起来Yeah,
Rootie even retired your barstool.
哇 那是…谢谢Wow, that's-
- Thanks.
但是 是 没死But, yeah, not dead.
就是寻找一些好运气 就像萝蒂所说Just looking for a
little good luck, like Rootie said.
我怎么这么没礼貌Where are my manners?
我是萝蒂 这家热带果汁酒吧的老板I'm Rootie, the proprietor
of this tropical juice bar
也是自封的坏运之地市长and the self-appointed mayor of Bad Luck.
萝蒂 很高兴见到你 我是山姆Nice to
meet you, Rootie. I'm Sam.
你是那个弄坏了电梯的小精灵Hey, you're that leprechaun who broke the elevator.
实际上是人类 而且是的 很抱歉弄坏了电梯Human actually, and yeah.
Sorry about that.
是人类啊 这可是第一次Human, huh?
Well, that's a first.
嗨 鲍勃 我们把你的凳子拿下来Hey, Bob.
We'll get your stool down for ya.
胶带 飞进来了Duct tape, flying in!
伙计们别担心 我们不能久留Don't worry about it, guys.
We can't stick around.
- 我们需要你的帮助 - 尽管说 怎么了
- We need your help.
- Name it. What's going on?
运气线断了 随机系统坏了Well, the luck lines
have detached, the Randomizer is broken,
我们正漂浮在空虚里 没有真正存在的目的and we're floating off into the
void with no real purpose to exist.
我们还以为只是把一条线弄短路了We thought we just short-circuited a wire.
我们没意识到我们弄坏了全世界We didn't realize we
had broken the whole world.
不是你们 是我们干的It wasn't you guys.
It was us.
有东西坏了并且不是我们的错  老兄 阿门Something broke, and it wasn't our fault?
Amen, brother.
但是可能还有一种方法能修好But there might still be
a way to fix it.
我之前在这的时候看见一道绿光When I was here before,
I saw a green light,
我真希望那是好运气which I'm really hoping is good luck.
是的 我们有一些 在幸运投篮里Oh, yeah, we've got some.
It's in the Lucky Shot.
幸运投篮Lucky Shot?
好耶 臭臭 漂亮Yeah! Way to go, Stinky!
好啦 跟我来All right, follow me.
鲍勃 你走后发生的Happened after you left, Bob.
我在修裂缝的时候碰到了这条管子I was out fixing cracks
when I backed into this pipe
结果一点好运气流了出来and a little good luck floated out.
所以我把它收集起来 直接放进了幸运篮框里So I gathered it up and
dropped it straight into the Lucky Shot.
我想这样每个人都能感受到一点好运气Figured that way everybody could
experience a little good luck.
- 你明白我的意思吧  - 但是它们怎么办
- You know what I mean?
- But what about them?
你在开玩笑吗You're kidding?
它们就找其他东西团结起来They'll just find something else to rally around.
这是坏运气的一个好处 它教会了你如何改变视角It's one of the benefits of bad luck.
It teaches you to pivot.
我从未那样想过I never really thought about it that way.
- 拜托 - 一定有东西坏了
- Come on!
- Something must be broken.
讨厌Bummer.
好吧 飞盘高尔夫怎么样Okay.
Frisbee golf, anyone?
明白我的意思了吗See what I'm saying?
而且你一旦修好了随机系统And once you've fixed the Randomizer,
我毫不怀疑总有一天我会再找到一些I have no doubt, one day,
I'll find some more.
萝蒂 谢谢你 我们也需要一些坏运气尘埃Thank you, Rootie.
And we'll need some bad luck dust too.
随便拿 这里多的是Have at it.
Plenty of that around.
如果你需要我们的帮助 说一声就行And if you could use our
help up there, just say the word.
"一声"Word.
好吧 赶紧去吧Well, giddy up!
我们得把这个给那条龙We gotta get this to the Dragon.
它不想看见我们 我们刚毁了它的世界She won't be happy to see us.
We just wrecked her world.
我想我们认识一个它愿意见的人I think we know someone
she will be happy to see.
我们怎么没发现她是个人类呢How could I miss
that she was a human?
一个高大的小精灵A tall leprechaun?
他们怎么敢出现在这里How dare they show up here?
是谁Who is it?
是鲍勃、那个女孩和一只独角兽It's Bob, the girl and a unicorn.
杰夫Jeff?
我的老天 我不记得这么困难Guter Kummer,
I don't remember it being that tough.
当然了 上次我还年轻力壮Of course, last
time I was a stallion.
已经过了100年It has been a hundred years.
贝贝 见到你真好Sch?n dich zu sehen, Babe.
海姆达尔Heimdall.
你们还敢来这里You got a lot of nerve coming here.
贝贝 听听他们要说的话Hear them out, Babe.
一点好运气 也许足够修好随机系统了A little good luck.
It might be enough to fix the Randomizer.
它从哪来的Where did it come from?
坏运之地Bad Luck.
不知怎么的 好运气到了那里 而且那里的生物非常善良 愿意分享Somehow it made its way
down there, and they were kind enough to share.
我们需要你打造两块新石头We need you to forge two new stones.
就像你做这个一样Just like when you made this.
你还留着它You still have it.
我从未摘下过I never took it off.
贝贝 你古老的龙火焰有这个力量Your ancient dragon
flames have the power, Babe.
我相信你还记得 如何挥舞你那炙热的火焰吧I trust you remember how
to wield your burning hot Feuer?
这是个挑战吗Was that a dare?
看看我是不是还能做到Let's see if I've still got it.
这是什么Was ist das?
你说你需要两块石头 好啦You said you needed two stones. Voilà!
但是你做了三个But you made three.
那个坏运石只是热一下身The bad luck stone was just a warm-up.
这些是给随机系统用的And these are for the Randomizer.
贝贝 你疯了吗Have you lost your brain marbles, Babe?
因为你太清楚了 随机系统需要一个好运Because you know very well
that das Randomizer needs a good luck
和一个坏运石and a bad luck stone.
真的如此吗 两块石头没错Does it though?
Two stones, sure.
但是告诉我哪里写着不能都是幸运石But show me where it
says they can't both be lucky.
这是我们都在等待的时刻This is the moment
we've all been waiting for.
有了这两块石头 我们能够消除坏运气With these two stones,
we can eliminate bad luck
还有随之而来的一切 挫折感、孤独感…and all that goes with it.
The frustration, the loneliness, the--
- 等等 但是… - 山姆 你自己说的
- Wait. But--
- You said it yourself, Sam.
没有坏运气 你的世界 可以看上去和我们的一样Without bad luck, your
world could look just like ours.
拜拜Toodle-oo!
下是向上Down to go up.
我不能让你放进两块幸运石I can't let you
place two good luck stones.
胡说八道 每个人永远都有好运气Nonsense.
Good luck for everyone all the time.
山姆 我们能够实现We can make that happen, Sam.
特别是你应该希望那样You, of all people, should want that.
我知道坏运气可能很糟糕 尤其是霉运接连不断I know bad luck can
be terrible, especially when it keeps coming.
- 但我们还是需要它 - 需要它
- But we still need it.
- Need it?
坏运气对我来说唯一的作用 就是毁掉我的世界、让我心碎The only thing bad luck ever did for
me was break my world and break my heart.
不 是我毁掉了你的世界No.
It was me who broke your world.
是坏运之地帮助你恢复一切It's Bad Luck that's here
helping put it back together.
- 这种事情难免发生 - 不是这里
- Hey, these things happen.
- Not here.
- 我们出发 - 别担心
- There we go.
- Don't worry.
我知道你担心让坏运气进来I know you're afraid
to let bad luck in.
你觉得这是你孤独的原因 我过去也这么想You think it's the reason you're alone.
I did too.
我曾把生活中出现的问题都归咎于坏运气I blamed bad luck for everything
that went wrong in my life.
但是来到了这里 我意识到 它让一些事情得以顺利发展But coming here,
I realized that it also made some things go very right.
没有我的坏运气 我不会遇到海瑟和鲍勃Without my bad luck,
I wouldn't have met Hazel or Bob.
而且你也永远不会遇到你一生的挚爱And you would've never met
the love of your life.
你在说什么What are you talking about?
你遇到杰夫恰恰是因为它被厄运缠身You only met Jeff because
he'd been doused by bad luck.
也就是说 它没有将你们分开Which means, it didn't tear you apart.
最初是坏运气让你们走到了一起Bad luck brought you
together in the first place.
你以为你的生物们无法承受坏运气You think your creatures can't endure bad luck,
但是它们能承受、也将会去承受but they can, and they will.
并且你也可以And so can you.
你们无需害怕坏运气 因为你们拥有彼此You don't have to fear
bad luck because you have each other.
这让你们成为我所认识的最幸运的生物And that makes you
the luckiest creatures I know.
天啊 如果好和坏运气可以最终共存Why, if good and bad luck
can at long last live side by side,
那么这是我最想看到的了then I would love nothing more.
也轮不到我来把生活中的所有神秘感带走Far be it from me to
take all the mystery out of life.
那就让它们并存吧Both it is.
山姆Sam!
我们这些有地位的幸运女士 应该团结起来 你觉得呢We lucky ladies of
stature oughta stick together, don't you think?
是的Oh, yes.
山姆 谢谢你Thank you, Sam.
好的 一杯超炫香蕉女妖鸡尾酒All right!
One bad-break banana banshee coming down.
抱歉 树根Sorry, Root.
没关系 佛瑞德 你知道我总是做两份 以防万一嘛No problem, Fred.
You know I always make two, just in case.
什么声音What was that?
我们已经想你们了We miss you already.
"我们"-"We"?
- Sam!
- 山姆 鲍勃 - 嗨 萝蒂
- Sam. Bob.
- Hey, Rootie.
- 好运气来到坏运之地 - 还有毛柠檬酒吧
- Good Luck in Bad Luck.
- And Hairy Lemon.
这个果汁酒吧可真漂亮Now, this is a good-looking juice bar.
对 幸运之地的第一家热带果汁酒吧Yeah.
First tropical juice bar in the Land of Luck.
我们是带着礼物来的 一个礼物We come bearing gifts.
Or, well, gift rather.
这是给幸运投篮的It's for the Lucky Shot.
它真漂亮She sure is a beauty.
这是对你们帮助的一点谢意It's a small token of
thanks for coming to our aid.
龙女士 我们很乐意帮忙It was our pleasure, Ms.
The Dragon.
而且我们非常感激你来这里做客And we sure do appreciate
you dropping in for a visit.
我早就应该来了I should have come long ago.
而且我们要感谢我们倒霉的朋友山姆 让我们聚到了一起Und we have our unlucky Freund
Sam to thank for bringing us all together.
拉脱维亚 你真棒Way to go, Latvia!
拉脱维亚Latvia!
山姆Sam!
说到我的坏运气Speaking of my bad luck,
我要谢谢你们把它都送给了我I'd like to thank you guys
for sending it all my way.
轮胎爆裂、烤面包有果酱的那面先着地 钥匙掉进下水道里The flat tires, the toast
jam-side-down, the keys in the sewer.
嘿 那是我干的Hey, that was me!
不是都那么好玩 但我不会改变任何一件事情It wasn't all fun, but
I wouldn't change a single thing.
山姆 你把它放进幸运投篮吧 好不好Fire her up.
What do you say, Sam?
- 鲍勃 投个篮吧 - 来吧 鲍勃
- Take a shot, Bob.
- Come on, Bob!
鲍勃 你觉得怎么样 准备好回家了吗Hey!
So, what do you say, Bob?
Ready to come home?
听上去这些家伙把你的酒吧凳修好了Sounds like the guys got your barstool fixed
准备等你就坐了and ready for your little cat butt.
伙计们 多谢Thanks, guys.
我们其实希望鲍勃能留在好运之地Well, we were actually hoping
Bob might stay in Good Luck.
船长说你可以继续以前的工作The Captain said you
could have your job back.
是的 尽管你的犯罪记录越来越多 杰瑞说你是只好划线猫Yeah, despite your growing rap sheet,
Gerry claims you're a good line cat.
所以 回来吧So, come on back.
我们给你做了这个 你的专属幸运硬币And we made you
this, your very own lucky penny.
哇Wow.
鲍勃 你一直渴望的幸运一生A lucky life just
like you always wanted, Bob.
我真为你高兴I'm so happy for you.
鲍勃 恭喜你Good for you, Bob.
船长 多谢 但是我不能接受Thanks,
Captain, but I can't accept.
- 老板  - 鲍勃
- Boss?
- Bob?
你们都是我不配拥有的好朋友You're all better friends than I deserve.
那倒是真的Well, that's true.
杰瑞 特别是你 我们还是朋友Especially you, Gerry.
And friends we will stay.
但至于我在哪里度过余生…But as for where I live
out the rest of my days--
如果我可以 我想和山姆 在她的世界一同度过If I can,
I'd like to spend them with Sam, in her world.
做你永久的家人Be your forever family?
我和你 一个永久的家Me and you, a forever family?
我太愿意了I'd really love that.
你意识到正在抱着我呢吧You realize you're hugging me, right?
是的 而且你最好习惯我的拥抱Yes.
And you better get used to it.
免费提供汁液饮料Juice drinks on the house!
是的 女士 加热吧 我们要叫它幸运龙Yes, ma'am. Heat it up.
We're gonna call that the Lucky Dragon.
一年后
经理 萨曼莎
迷你棕榈树 一些散装豆子Mini palm tree.
Some bulk beans.
我在做沙包I'm making bean bags,
我想混合在一起可能会很好 你知道 手感and I thought a mix
might be nice, you know, in your hand.
你好 你…在…哪
一块带绳子的肥皂 总共13.57美元And one soap-on-a-rope
brings your total to $13.57.
让我找一下我的信用卡Let me just find my credit card.
等一下 又是那个豆豆妇人吗
代我向她问好 然后告诉她快一点
- 我找到卡了 - 太好了
- Found my card!
- Great.
查尔斯女士 给您Here you go, Ms. Charles.
山姆经理 交给我吧Hey, I got this,
Sam the manager.
马文 祝福你Bless you, Marvin.
- 祝您愉快 - 周一见
- Have a great time!
- See you Monday!
我就不该给你买手机I should never have
gotten you a cell phone.
我停不下来 抱歉 我有问题 我就是为拇指打字而生I can't stop. I'm sorry.
I have a problem.
I was born to thumb-type.
地图说要九分钟 但我们走捷径Map says nine minutes,
but we'll take the shortcut.
世界上最好的女儿
他们来了They're here!
山姆Sam!
- 鲍勃 过来 - 海瑟 抱得也太紧了
- Come here, Bob.
- I say, Hazel.
This is a tight one.
嗨 山姆 嗨 鲍勃Hi, Sam. Hi, Bob.
坐Sit.
宾果 不错 谁是你的主人Good work, Bingo.
Who's your master?
谁是你的主人 对 是鲍勃 鲍勃是你的主人Who's your master? That's right. Bob is.
Bob is your master.
妈妈再见 爸爸再见Bye, Mom. Bye, Dad.
她就是有点兴奋She's just a little excited.
是的 我也是Yeah, me too.
海瑟真幸运找到了你们Hazel's really lucky she found you guys.
我们很确定幸运的是我们I'm pretty sure we're the lucky ones.
我们星期天在这里吃饭时见 5点钟And we'll see you here for dinner on Sunday!
Five o'clock.
我们有鲍勃最爱吃的We're having Bob's favorite.
我们一定来We'll be here.
鲍勃听到没 星期天有帕尼尼You hear that, Bob?
Paninis on Sunday.
美味的肉面包Tasty meat bread.
太好了Bingo.
不是你Not you!
我的新生活和我想象的完全不同My new life is nothing
like the one I pictured.
比我想得更好It's better.
当然 事情并不总按计划发展Things don't always
go as planned, of course.
除非 你为此做好准备Unless, well, you plan for them.
最终 你可能会说坏运气 带给我世界上最幸运的东西In the end, you might say that bad
luck led me to the luckiest thing in the world.
或许它是好运气Or was it good luck?
无论如何 我找到了我永久的家人Whatever it was,
I found my forever family.
不会离开、永远都在的那种The kind that doesn't leave.
They stick.
而且为了这一切 我愿意再来一次And I'd do it
all over again to get here.
家
完
字幕翻译：张欣